<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debugging on Engineering Manager made in Wales but working in Germany - Danny Croft</title>
    <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/tag/debugging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debugging on Engineering Manager made in Wales but working in Germany - Danny Croft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 19:31:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/tag/debugging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to enable the Safari Debug Menu</title>
      <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/how-to-enable-the-safari-debug-menu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 19:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/how-to-enable-the-safari-debug-menu/</guid>
      <description>This past month I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered a few people that didn&amp;rsquo;t know about the Debug menu that is available in Safari. Granted, for most engineers it won&amp;rsquo;t be of any use, but for some it will be invaluable.
 Open up the terminal (Mac OSX) Enter the following and hit enter: defaults write com.apple.Safari -IncludeInternalDebugMenu 1 Restart/Open Safari  Note: This can be undone by changing 1 to 0 in the above command followed by a restart of Safari.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debugging JavaScript using Firebug – An alternative to alert();</title>
      <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/debugging-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 16:22:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/debugging-javascript/</guid>
      <description>So as you may already know, Firebug must be one of the most important tools a developer can have in their utility belt.
The more I use Firebug, the more I realise that I&amp;rsquo;m not using it to its full potential. One of the most useful aspects of Firebug is its ability to help me debug code fast.
It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how many developers out there have Firebug installed, but when debugging JavaScript always resort to using the alert(); function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
