<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Html5 on Software Engineer made in Wales but working in Germany - Danny Croft</title>
    <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/categories/html5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Html5 on Software Engineer made in Wales but working in Germany - Danny Croft</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 16:16:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/categories/html5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript Gig Finder</title>
      <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/javascript-gig-finder/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2011 16:16:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/javascript-gig-finder/</guid>
      <description>This week the guys at Songkick gave me access to their API. I had some spare time today to get to know it better and generally mess around with it.
I decided that what I really could do with was a simple way of finding out what gigs and concerts are on near me. So using the data kindly provided by Songkick (thanks guys!) I went ahead and built just that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript W3C Unicorn Bookmarklet</title>
      <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/javascript-w3c-unicorn-bookmarklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2011 19:59:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/javascript-w3c-unicorn-bookmarklet/</guid>
      <description>I use the W3C Unicorn Validator for almost all my markup validation needs. However every time I need to validate something I almost always end up googling &amp;ldquo;W3C Unicorn&amp;rdquo;. Which I admit is still pretty fast, but I wanted to cut as much faff out of that process as possible.
So today (as in just this minute), I made a JavaScript bookmarklet that will help me trim the fat as it were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTML5 Canvas - Fireworks</title>
      <link>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/html5-canvas-fireworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2010 18:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.dannycroft.co.uk/html5-canvas-fireworks/</guid>
      <description>After finally getting some free time (Christmas Eve). I decided to action some of the items I learnt at the Full Frontal conference in November.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tested the demo in: (in order of performance)
 Safari 5.0.3 Chrome 8.0.552 Firefox 3.6.13 Opera 10.10  Here&amp;rsquo;s what I came up with: http://bit.ly/gRYQkt
You can download all the source files here: http://bit.ly/gUPpxI</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>